* en
*  Suche

Hauptmenü

    -------------

    ---------------

    ------------
    
    * ### [Manuals | eReader I tab](#)

    * ### [FAQ](#)

* tolino webreader
    * en

* 
    
    [NEW: Compact reading pleasure in color
    --------------------------------------](https://mytolino.com/products/tolino-shine-color/)
    
    The small all-rounder impresses with its compact and lightweight design and offers unlimited reading and listening pleasure thanks to the latest technology, color display and audiobook function.
    
    * NEW: Color display with 4,096 color
    * NEW: Enjoy audio books via Bluetooth
    * smartLight for optimum lighting day and night

* 
    
    [NEW: The special reading experience in color
    --------------------------------------------](https://mytolino.com/products/tolino-vision-color/)
    
    The tolino vision color brings your favorite content to life with its new color display in up to 4,096 colors and also offers a first-class reading and now also listening experience via Bluetooth.
    
    * NEW: Color display with 4,096 colors
    * NEW: Take notes, mark up, design with the new tolino stylus
    * NEW: Enjoy audio books via Bluetooth

* 
    
    [NEW: The smart introduction to digital reading
    ----------------------------------------------](https://mytolino.com/products/tolino-shine/)
    
    Small size, big content – the best introduction to digital reading. A new feature is the audio book function, which allows you to enjoy your audio books wirelessly via Bluetooth using headphones or speakers.
    
    * NEW: Enjoy audio books via Bluetooth
    * smartLight for optimal lighting day and night
    * Water protection for carefree reading in the bath or by the pool

* 
    
    [NEW: tolino stylus - note, mark, design on the tolino
    -----------------------------------------------------](https://mytolino.com/products/tolino-stylus/)
    
    The tolino stylus is the perfect addition to your tolino vision color. Write handwritten notes directly in eBooks and PDFs or create notebooks for everything you want to record.
    
    * Create handwritten notes directly in eBooks and PDFs.
    * Highlight important text passages with the intuitive highlight button
    * Easily remove notes you no longer need thanks to the eraser function

* 
    
    [tolino app - reading as flexible as ever
    ----------------------------------------](https://mytolino.com/tolino-app/)
    
    Turn your smartphone or tablet into an eBook reader with the free tolino app, use it to enjoy audiobooks and discover many other useful functions:
    
    * Fixed layout for comics and manga
    * tolino iPad app with Apple Pencil support
    * tolino iOS app with Apple CarPlay support
    * Translation function
    * Family Sharing for eBooks and audiobooks

* 
    
    [Software Update
    ---------------](https://mytolino.com/software-updates-for-tolino-ereaders/)
    
    Here you find the current software version for your tolino ereader.

tolino shine color

### NEW: compact reading pleasure in color

* NEW: Color display with 4,096 colors
* NEW: Enjoy audio books via Bluetooth
* smartLight: adjust the lighting according to the time of day

tolino eBook-Reader
===================

tolino eReader

Enjoy reading like never before
-------------------------------

* ereader tolino page 2
* ereader tolino shine 4
* ereader vision 6
* ereader epos 3

tolino vision color

### NEW: The special reading experience in color

* NEW: Color display with 4,096 colors
* NEW: Take notes, mark up, design with the new, separately available tolino stylus
* NEW: Enjoy audio books via Bluetooth

tolino stylus

### NEW: create notes, highlight and scribble on your tolino

* Create handwritten notes directly in eBooks and PDFs.
* Highlight important text passages with the intuitive highlight button
* Easily remove notes that are no longer needed

tolino shine

### NEW: The smart introduction to digital reading

* NEW: Enjoy audio books via Bluetooth
* smartLight: adjust the lighting according to the time of day
* Water protection for carefree reading in the bathtub or by the pool

tolino epos 3

### The maximum in reading comfort

* 8-inch E Ink display and powerful Quad Core processor: ideal for large fonts and magnification mode
* SmartLight: adjustment of the lighting according to the time of day
* Water protection: relaxed reading in the bathtub

Openness, freedom and the competence of the German bookseller
-------------------------------------------------------------

### tolino app

Browse, search, read – anywhere and on any device with the tolino app for all tolino booksellers.

### tolino cloud

Use the tolino cloud free of charge.

### Open system

Open system for maximum flexibility

### tolino webreader

With the tolino Webreader you can read your e-books directly on your laptop or tablet via your internet browser.

    * Selfpublishing with tolino

### Download tolino app from the App Store:

### Keep in touch with tolino:

© tolino media GmbH & Co. KG All rights reserved

Privacy Preference

We need your consent before you can continue to visit our website. If you are under 16 and wish to give your consent to volunteer services, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission. We use cookies and other technologies on our website. Some of them are essential, while others help us to improve this website and your experience. In this way, information on your terminal device regarding your use of our website is accessed or stored on your terminal device. Personal data maybe processed (e.g. IP-adresses), e.g. for personalized ads and content or ad and content measurement. Click "Accept all" to give your consent or "Save" to allow only essential cookies. You can also select "Individual privacy settings" to change settings in detail as well as to get more information about the types of cookies we use, providers used and the processing of your personal data.  
  
For more information about how we use your data, please see our [Privacy Policy](https://mytolino.com/privacy-policy/). You can change your selection at any time at [Cookie Settings](#)

Privacy Preference

* Essential 
* Statistics 
* Marketing 
* External media 

Privacy Preference

If you are under 16 and wish to give your consent to volunteer services, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission. We use cookies and other technologies on our website. Some of them are essential, while others help us to improve this website and your experience. In this way, information on your terminal device regarding your use of our website is accessed or stored on your terminal device. Personal data maybe processed (e.g. IP-adresses), e.g. for personalized ads and content or ad and content measurement. Click "Accept all" to give your consent or "Save" to allow only essential cookies. You can also select "Individual privacy settings" to change settings in detail as well as to get more information about the types of cookies we use, providers used and the processing of your personal data.  
  
For more information about how we use your data, please see our [Privacy Policy](https://mytolino.com/privacy-policy/). Here you will find an overview of all cookies used. You can give your consent to whole categories or display further information and select certain cookies.

Privacy Preference

Essential (2)

Essential cookies enable basic functions and are necessary for the proper functioning of the website.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Name | Borlabs Cookie |
| Provider | Owner of this website, [Legal Notice](https://mytolino.com/imprint/) |
| Purpose | Saves the visitors preferences selected in the Cookie Box of Borlabs Cookie. |
| Cookie name | borlabs-cookie |
| Cookie term | 1 Jahr |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Name | WPML |
| Provider | Owner of this website |
| Purpose | Stores the current language. |
| Privacy Policy | [https://mytolino.com/privacy-policy/](https://mytolino.com/privacy-policy/) |
| Cookie name | \_icl\_\*, wpml\_\*, wp-wpml\_\* |
| Cookie term | 1 Tag |

Statistics (1)

Statistics 

Statistics Cookies collect information anonymously. This information helps us understand how our visitors use our website.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Accept | Matomo |
| Name | Matomo |
| Provider | Mytolino |
| Purpose | Cookie by Matomo used for website analytics. Generates statistical data on how the visitor uses the website. |
| Privacy Policy | [https://mytolino.com/privacy-policy/](https://mytolino.com/privacy-policy/) |
| Cookie name | \_pk\_\*.\* |
| Cookie term | 13 Monate |

Marketing (1)

Marketing 

Marketing cookies are used by third-party vendors or publishers to display personalized advertisements. They do this by tracking visitors across websites.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Accept | Facebook Pixel |
| Name | Facebook Pixel |
| Provider | Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland |
| Purpose | Cookie by Facebook used for website analytics, ad targeting, and ad measurement. |
| Privacy Policy | [https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies) |
| Cookie name | \_fbp,act,c\_user,datr,fr,m\_pixel\_ration,pl,presence,sb,spin,wd,xs |
| Cookie term | Sitzung / 1 Jahr |

External media (6)

External media 

Content from video platforms and social media platforms is blocked by default. If cookies from external media are accepted, access to this content no longer requires manual consent.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Accept | YouTube |
| Name | YouTube |
| Provider | Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland |
| Purpose | Used to unblock YouTube content. |
| Privacy Policy | [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) |
| Host(s) | google.com |
| Cookie name | NID |
| Cookie term | 6 Monate |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Accept | Facebook |
| Name | Facebook |
| Provider | Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland |
| Purpose | Wird verwendet, um Facebook-Inhalte zu entsperren. |
| Privacy Policy | [https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation) |
| Host(s) | .facebook.com |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Accept | Google Maps |
| Name | Google Maps |
| Provider | Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland |
| Purpose | Wird zum Entsperren von Google Maps-Inhalten verwendet. |
| Privacy Policy | [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) |
| Host(s) | .google.com |
| Cookie name | NID |
| Cookie term | 6 Monate |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Accept | Instagram |
| Name | Instagram |
| Provider | Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland |
| Purpose | Wird verwendet, um Instagram-Inhalte zu entsperren. |
| Privacy Policy | [https://www.instagram.com/legal/privacy/](https://www.instagram.com/legal/privacy/) |
| Host(s) | .instagram.com |
| Cookie name | pigeon\_state |
| Cookie term | Sitzung |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Accept | OpenStreetMap |
| Name | OpenStreetMap |
| Provider | Openstreetmap Foundation, St John’s Innovation Centre, Cowley Road, Cambridge CB4 0WS, United Kingdom |
| Purpose | Wird verwendet, um OpenStreetMap-Inhalte zu entsperren. |
| Privacy Policy | [https://wiki.osmfoundation.org/wiki/Privacy\_Policy](https://wiki.osmfoundation.org/wiki/Privacy_Policy) |
| Host(s) | .openstreetmap.org |
| Cookie name | \_osm\_location, \_osm\_session, \_osm\_totp\_token, \_osm\_welcome, \_pk\_id., \_pk\_ref., \_pk\_ses., qos\_token |
| Cookie term | 1-10 Jahre |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Accept | Twitter |
| Name | Twitter |
| Provider | Twitter International Company, One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street, Dublin 2, D02 AX07, Ireland |
| Purpose | Wird verwendet, um Twitter-Inhalte zu entsperren. |
| Privacy Policy | [https://twitter.com/privacy](https://twitter.com/privacy) |
| Host(s) | .twimg.com, .twitter.com |
| Cookie name | \_\_widgetsettings, local\_storage\_support\_test |
| Cookie term | Unbegrenzt |
